Igor Kozlovsky



Location: Minsk, Belarus.

LinkedIn Profile:

https://www.linkedin.com/in/igor-kozlovsky-9017a1b3/

GitHub Profile:

https://github.com/igor-lemon

Skype: igor-lemon

Mail: igor.lemon.kozlovsky@gmail.com

About me

My name is Igor Kozlovsky. I have over 9 years of experience in software development. I enjoy developing rich web apps and use cutting edge dev tools on real projects. I value projects with sense, the ones, that change people's lives and try to avoid routine 9-to-5 jobs. I prefer working with friendly teams where I can share my experience and get a new experience in return. If this is the kind of team and project you have, I think we should talk.

Education

 2006 - 2011 - Software Engineer & Computer Science at Gomel State Technical University.

Languages

- English Intermediate+
- Russian Native
- Belarusian Native
- Ukrainian Passive Advanced (understanding and reading);

Professional skills

- Full software development cycle, Scrum.
- Team leading scrum mastering and delivery planning in small teams of 2-6 people.
- Operation systems (Windows, Mac, Linux) and virtualization.
- **Programming languages:** JavaScript, NodeJS, PHP (>= 5.6).
- Additional: CSS3, HTML5, LESS, SaaS.
- Libs, Tools & Frameworks: React, Redux, Saga, AngularJS 1.x, VanillaJS, WebPack (1.x, 2.x), Electron. PHP Frameworks (Yii 1.x, Yii 2.x).
- Testing tools: Enzyme, Jest.
- **DB** software: MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis.
- CMS: Wordpress, Drupal, Joomla.
- Version Control Systems: GIT (work with GitFlow).
- Issue Tracking Systems: JIRA, GitHub, GitLab.

Additional Skills:

- DevOps: Docker, Docker Compose, Docke Machine.
- Networking: TCP/IP, HTTP, SSL, etc..
- Clouds: DigitalOcean, Selectel, AWS.
- Base DevOps skills: Nginx, Postfix, DoveCot, Supervisor, Gearman, MySQL, MongoDB, PostgreSQL, Redis NodeJS, PHP-FPM.

Additional experience:

• I'm constantly studying new things on special resources like MDN, egghead.io, etc.

Professional experience:

• 2017 - 2017 - CobaCode. Stack: React, Redux, Saga, VanillaJS, jQuery.

Position: Developer.

What I made: Developed a cross-platform TV application for Tizen, WebOS, etc... I got a new experience in developing apps for TV platforms. It's awesome!

• 2016 - Present - DockStation. Stack: Electron, React, Redux.

Position: Founder, Architect, Developer.

What I made: Complete development of the project from 0 to the finished product. Learned Docker, Docker API.

 2015 - 2017 - Linnovate. StackSight project. MEAN Stack: MongoDB, NodeJS + Angular 1.x., jQuery.

Position: Full-Stack developer.

What I made: I made AngularJS modules and binding it to an API. Made PHP SDK. Developed and bound to the API modules for popular CMS: Wordpress, Drupal, Magento. Built additional modules for Symphony and Meteor. Made markup.

2015 - 2015 - SocialJet. Stack: Yii 1.x, Native JS, jQuery.

Position: Full-Stack developer.

What I made: Developed and connected to an API inside cabinet of customers. Made markup.

2015 - 2015 - MParts. Full software development cycle: developed SaaS for easy looking for spare part via a tender method. Stack: PHP, Yii 2.x, PostgreSQL, Redis, Supervisor, Gearman, jQuery.

Position: Founder, Architect, Developer.

What I made: Complete development of the project from 0 to the finished product. Made architecture of the project. Made scripts for parsing info about auto from different sources. Made scalable structure. Full covered with automatic tests. Upped server on NGinx. Upped a manager of queues. Markup.

 2014 - 2015 - OnlinerIO. Full software development cycle: developed SaaS for watching user activity on the social network VK. Stack: PHP, Yii 1.x, MongoDB, Redis, Supervisor, Gearman, jQuery.

Position: Founder, Architect, Developer.

What I made: Complete development of the project from 0 to the finished product. Made deep integration with VK API. Integration with payment aggregators. Integration with outside services for sending SMS and Notifications. Made many optimizations of algorithms which increased user processing: from 20000 per minute to 1M+ per minute. Upped server on NGinx. Upped a manager of queues. Markup.

2014 - 2015 - E-mind. PHP Developer. Stack: PHP, MySQL, Native JS, jQuery.
 Position: PHP Developer. Markup Frontend.

What I made: Made CRM for tracking time of developers. Made a real-estate aggregator which parse real-estate announcements from many outside sites and after converts it announcements to a single format. Markup.

2014 – 2014 - NightOut. PHP, MySQL, jQuery.

Position: Developer.

What I made: Developed calendar and photo modules. Markup.

 2012 – 2014 - MedSoNet. Full software development cycle: built & developed Medical Social Network. Stack: PHP, MySQL, Native JS, jQuery.

Position: Architect, Developer.

What I made: Complete development of the project from 0 to the finished product.

Made remote monitoring system for patients based on Joomla Framework. Integration

with payment aggregators. Modified a forum module for patient needs. Markup.

• 2007 - 2011 - Freelance.

Position: PHP Developer.

What I made: Many many awesome stuff. Most often it was: e-commerce, landing pages, personal sites. Design. Markup. More info and reviews you can see here: https://www.fl.ru/users/lemon007/